A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Rural Poverty and Resources Department Correspondence FA1404
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Rural Poverty and Resources Department Correspondence
1995 December - 1996 January
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1404
.8 Cubic Feet 2 document containers
Scope and Contents
The collections contains correspondence sent on behalf of the Ford Foundation Program Division, Rural Poverty and Resources Program to Ford Foundation staff, grantees, and grant applicants in 1995 and 1996. Officers who sent and reviewed the correspondence include: Director of the program, E. Walter Coward, Jr., the Deputy Director, Lisa Mensah, and Program Officers, Elizabeth C. Campbell, Doreen Dun, Eric Holst, Frances F. Korten, Jeffrey T. Olson, Chris Page, Peggy Greaves, and Sharon Ebron
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2018:017
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas.
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically into one series: Rural Poverty and Resources Department Correspondence
Ford Foundation; Rural poverty -- United States; Rural poverty and resourses
- Rural Poverty and Resources Department Correspondence, 1
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1995 December 4-21 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1995 December 13-29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 January 3-15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 January 9-26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 January 29-February 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 February 13-23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 February 29-March 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 March 12-19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 March 20-April 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 April 12-30 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 May 1-14 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 May 15-30 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 May 28-June 14 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 June 17-28 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 July 3-23 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 July 22-31 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 August 1-16 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 August 16-30 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Circulating Chronological File, 1996 September 3-27 (Box 2, Folder 19)